<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hadiths>
    <hadith>
        Narrated 'Umar bin Al-Khattab (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ), reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The deeds are considered by the intentions, and a person will get the reward according to his
        intention. So whoever emigrated for Allah and His Messenger, his emigration will be for Allah and His Messenger;
        and whoever emigrated for worldly benefits or for a woman to marry, his emigration would be for what he
        emigrated for." [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Narrated 'A`ishah (رَضِيَ اَللَّهُ عَنْهَا) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said, "An army will raid the Ka`bah and when it reaches a desert land, all of them will be swallowed up by the
        earth.'' She asked; "O Messenger of Allah! Why all of them?'' He answered, "All of them will be swallowed by the
        earth but they will be raised for Judgement according to their intentions.''[Al-Bukhari and Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir bin Abdullah Al-Ansari (رضي الله عنهما) reported: We accompanied the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) in an expedition when he said, "There are some men in Al-Madinah who are with you wherever you march
        and whichever valley you cross. They have not joined you in person because of their illness.'' In another
        version he said: "They share the reward with you.'' [Muslim]. "
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ma`n bin Yazid bin Akhnas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) (he, his father and his grandfather, all were Companions)
        reported: My father set aside some dinars for charity and gave them to a man in the mosque. I went to that man
        and took back those dinars. He said: "I had not intended you to be given.'' So we went to Messenger of Allah
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ), and put forth the matter before him. He said to my father, "Yazid, you have
        been rewarded for what you intended.'' And he said to me, "Ma`n, you are entitled to what you have taken.''
        [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) narrated: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Allah does not look at your figures, nor at your attire but He looks at your hearts and accomplishments".
        [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa Al-Ash`ari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        was asked about who fights in the battlefield out of valour, or out of zeal, or out of hypocrisy, which of this
        is considered as fighting in the cause of Allah? He said: "He who fights in order that the Word of Allah remains
        the supreme, is considered as fighting in the cause of Allah". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Bakrah Ath-Thaqafi (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said:
        "When two Muslims are engaged in a combat against each other with their sword's and one is killed, both are
        doomed to Hell". I said, "O Messenger of Allah! As to the one who kills, it is understandable, but why the slain
        one?" He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) replied: "He was eager to kill his opponent". [Al-Bukhari and
        Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin `Abbas (رضي الله عنهما) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said
        that Allah, the Glorious, said: "Verily, Allah (SWT) has ordered that the good and the bad deeds be written
        down. Then He explained it clearly how (to write): He who intends to do a good deed but he does not do it, then
        Allah records it for him as a full good deed, but if he carries out his intention, then Allah the Exalted,
        writes it down for him as from ten to seven hundred folds, and even more. But if he intends to do an evil act
        and has not done it, then Allah writes it down with Him as a full good deed, but if he intends it and has done
        it, Allah writes it down as one bad deed". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I heard Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        saying: "By Allah, I seek Allah's forgiveness and repent to Him more than seventy times a day.'' [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Al-Agharr bin Yasar Al-Muzani (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) narrated that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said: "Turn you people in repentance to Allah and beg pardon of Him. I turn to Him in
        repentance a hundred times a day". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas bin Malik Al-Ansari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) the servant of the Messenger of Allah narrated: Messenger of
        Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Verily, Allah is more delighted with the repentance of His slave
        than a person who lost his camel in a desert land and then finds it (unexpectedly)". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa Al-Ash`ari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said:
        "Allah, the Exalted, will continue to stretch out His Hand in the night so that the sinners of the day may
        repent, and continue to stretch His Hand in the daytime so that the sinners of the night may repent, until the
        sun rises from the west". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) narrated: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "He
        who repents before the sun rises from the west, Allah will forgive him". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin `Umar bin Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنهما) reported that: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Allah accepts a slave's repentance as long as the latter is not on his death bed (that is,
        before the soul of the dying person reaches the throat)." [At-Tirmidhi, who categorised it as Hadith Hasan].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn 'Abbas and Anas bin Malik (رضي الله عنهما) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) said, "If a son of Adam were to own a valley full of gold, he would desire to have two. Nothing can
        fill his mouth except the earth (of the grave). Allah turns with mercy to him who turns to Him in repentance."
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Allah, the Exalted, smiles at two men, one of them killed the other and both will enter Jannah. The first is
        killed by the other while he is fighting in the Cause of Allah, and thereafter Allah will turn in mercy to the
        second and guide him to accept Islam and then he dies as a Shaheed (martyr) fighting in the Cause of Allah.''
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Malik Al-Harith bin Asim Al-Ash`ar (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said: "Wudu' is half of Salah; the utterance of (Al-hamdu lillah - all praise belongs
        to Allah) fills the Scales of good actions; the utterance of (Subhan Allah wa Al-hamdu lillah) (Allah is far
        removed from every imperfection and all praise belongs to Allah) fills the space between the heavens and the
        earth, and Salat (prayer) is light; and charity is the proof of Faith; and endurance is light, and the Qur'an is
        a plea in your favour or against you. Every person departs; he either ransoms it or puts it into perdition".
        [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sa'id Al-Khudri (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: Certain people of the Ansar asked the Messenger of
        Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) and he gave them; then they again asked him and he gave them until all
        what he possessed was exhausted. Then the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Whatever wealth I
        have, I will not withhold from you. Whosoever would be chaste and modest; Allah will keep him chaste and modest
        and whosoever would seek selfsufficiency, Allah will make him self-sufficient; and whosoever would be patient,
        Allah will give him patience, and no one is granted a gift better and more comprehensive than patience".
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Yahya Suhaib bin Sinan (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "How wonderful is the case of a believer; there is good for him in everything and this
        applies only to a believer. If prosperity attends him, he expresses gratitude to Allah and that is good for him;
        and if adversity befalls him, he endures it patiently and that is better for him". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: When the last illness of Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) made him unconscious, Fatimah (رضي الله عنها) exclaimed: "Ah, the distress of my dear father.'' He
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "There will be no distress for your father after today". When he died
        she said: "My father, Allah has called you back and you have responded to His Call. O father! Garden of Firdaus
        is your abode. O father! We announce to Jibril your death.'' When he was buried, she said: "Are you satisfied
        now that you put earth over (the grave of) Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)?'' [Al-Bukhari]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) passed by a woman who was
        crying over a grave and said, "Fear Allah and be patient.'' She said, "Away from me! My calamity has not
        befallen you and you are not aware of it.'' The woman was later told that it was the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) (who had advised her). She came to his door where she found no doorkeeper. She said, "(I am
        sorry) I did not know you.'' Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Patience is (becoming)
        only at the first (stroke) of grief". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Allah, the Exalted, says: 'I have no reward other than Jannah for a believing slave of Mine who remains patient
        for My sake when I take away his beloved one from among the inhabitants of the world". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (رَضِيَ اَللَّهُ عَنْهَا) reported: I asked the Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        about pestilence and he said, "It is a punishment which Allah sends upon whomsoever He wills, but Allah has made
        it as a mercy to the believers. Anyone who remains in a town which is plagued with pestilence maintaining
        patience expecting the reward from Allah, and knowing that nothing will befall him other than what Allah has
        foreordained for him, he would receive a reward of Shaheed". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: I heard the Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) saying,
        "Allah, the Glorious and Exalted said: `When I afflict my slave in his two dear things (i.e., his eyes), and he
        endures patiently, I shall compensate him for them with Jannah.". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Ata' bin Abu Rabah reported: Ibn `Abbas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) asked him whether he would like that he
        should show him a woman who is from the people Jannah. When he replied that he certainly would, he said, "This
        black woman, who came to the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) and said, `I suffer from epilepsy and
        during fits my body is exposed, so make supplication to Allah for me.' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        replied: 'If you wish you endure it patiently and you be rewarded with Jannah, or if you wish, I shall make
        supplication to Allah to cure you?' She said, 'I shall endure it.' Then she added: `But my body is exposed, so
        pray to Allah that it may not happen.' He (Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)) then supplicated for her."
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I can still recall as if I am seeing the Messenger of
        Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) resembling one of the Prophets whose people scourged him and shed his
        blood, while he wiped blood from his face, he said: "O Allah! Forgive my people, because they certainly do not
        know". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sa`id and Abu Hurairah (رضي الله عنهما) reported that the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said: "Never a believer is stricken with a discomfort, an illness, an anxiety, a grief or mental worry or even
        the pricking of a thorn but Allah will expiate his sins on account of his patience". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I visited the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) when he
        was suffering fever. I said, "You seem to be suffering greatly, O Messenger of Allah.'' The Prophet (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) replied, "Yes, I suffer as much as two persons.'' I said, "Is that because you have a
        double reward?'' He replied that was so and then said, "No Muslim is afflicted by a harm, be it the pricking of
        a thorn or something more (painful than that), but Allah thereby causes his sins to fall away just as a tree
        sheds its leaves". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said: "He whom Allah intends good, He makes him to suffer from some affliction". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Let not one of you wish for death because of a misfortune which befalls him. If he cannot help doing so, he
        should say: 'O Allah, keep me alive as long as You know that life is better for me, and make me die when death
        is better for me". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "When Allah intends good for His slave, He punishes him in this world, but when He intends an evil for His
        slave, He does not hasten to take him to task but calls him to account on the Day of Resurrection.''
        [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The
        strong man is not one who is good at wrestling, but the strong man is one who controls himself in a fit of
        rage.'' [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Sulaiman bin Surad (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I was sitting with the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) when two men began to quarrel and curse each other and the face of one of them turned red and the
        veins of his neck were swollen (from rage). Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "I know
        of a word, if he were to utter that, his rage would vanish and that is: A`udhu billahi minash-Shaitan nir-rajim
        (I seek refuge with Allah from Satan, the accursed).'' So they (Companions) said to him: "The Prophet (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) tells you to utter: 'I seek refuge with Allah from Satan, the accursed".
        [Al-Bukhariand Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Mu`adh bin Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The one
        who suppresses anger and has the power to give effect to it, will be called out by Allah, the Exalted, to the
        forefront of the creatures on the Day of Resurrection and he will be asked to choose any of the virgins (Hur) of
        his liking". [Abu Dawud and At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: A man asked the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) for
        an advice and he (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Do not get angry". The man repeated that several times
        and he replied, "Do not get angry". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "A
        Muslim, male or female, continues to remain under trial in respect of his life, property and offspring until he
        faces Allah, the Exalted, with no sin record". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "You
        will see after me favouritism and things which you will disapprove of.'' They submitted: "What do you order us
        to do (under such circumstances)?'' He replied, "Discharge your obligations and ask your rights from Allah".
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abdullah bin Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Truth leads to piety and piety leads to Jannah. A man persists in speaking the truth till he is enrolled with
        Allah as a truthful. Falsehood leads to vice and vice leads to the Fire (Hell), and a person persists on telling
        lies until he is enrolled as a liar".' [Agreed upon].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Hasan bin `Ali (رضي الله عنهما) said: I remember (these words) from Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ): "Give up what is doubtful to you for that which is not doubtful; for truth is peace of mind
        and falsehood is doubt". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sufyan (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported, in course of his detailed narration about Heraclius when the
        latter questioned him about the teachings of the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) He said that: He
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) told (us): "Worship Allah Alone and do not associate a thing with Him; and
        give up all that your ancestors said. "He also commands us to perform Salat (prayers), to speak the truth, to
        observe modesty and to strengthen the ties of kinship. [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Thabit from Sahl bin Hunaif (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said: "He who asks Allah for martyrdom, Allah will raise him to the high status of the martyrs, even if he dies
        on his bed". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Hakim bin Hizam (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said: "Both parties in a business transaction have a right to annul it so long as they have not separated; and
        if they tell the truth and make everything clear to each other (i.e., the seller and the buyer speak the truth,
        the seller with regard to what is purchased, and the buyer with regard to the money) they will be blessed in
        their transaction, but if they conceal anything and lie, the blessing on their transaction will be eliminated.''
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Dharr and Mu`adh bin Jabal (رضي الله عنهما) reported that: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Fear Allah wherever you are, do good deeds after doing bad ones, the former will wipe out the
        latter, and behave decently towards people". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn Abbas (رضي الله عنهما) said: One day, I was riding behind the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        when he said, "O boy! I will instruct you in some matters. Be watchful of Allah (Commandments of Allah), He will
        preserve you. Safeguard His Rights, He will be ever with you. If you beg, beg of Him Alone; and if you need
        assistance, supplicate to Allah Alone for help. And remember that if all the people gather to benefit you, they
        will not be able to benefit you except that which Allah had foreordained (for you); and if all of them gather to
        do harm to you, they will not be able to afflict you with anything other than that which Allah had pre-destined
        against you. The pens had been lifted and the ink had dried up". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: You indulge in (bad) actions which are more insignificant to you than a
        hair while we considered them at the time of Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) to be great
        destroying sins". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Shaddad bin Aus (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "A wise
        man is the one who calls himself to account (and refrains from doing evil deeds) and does noble deeds to benefit
        him after death; and the foolish person is the one who subdues himself to his temptations and desires and seeks
        from Allah the fulfillment of his vain desires". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "It
        is from the excellence of (a believer's) Islam that he should shun that which is of no concern to him".
        [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: It was asked, "O Messenger of Allah! Who is the most honourable
        amongst mankind?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The most honourable of them is one who is the
        most pious of them.'' They said, "We are not asking about this". He said, "Then, the most honourable of men was
        Yusuf (Joseph), the Prophet of Allah, the son of Allah's Prophet, who was the son of the Prophet of Allah, who
        was the son of the Khalil of Allah (i.e., Ibrahim (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ))' They said, "We are not
        asking you about this.'' He enquired, "Are you then asking me about the classes of the Arabs? The best of them
        in the Pre-Islamic Period of Ignorance are the best of them in Islam, provided they comprehend the religious
        knowledge". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sa`id Al-Khudri (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The
        life of the world is sweet and green. Allah makes you generations succeeding one another so that He may try you
        in respect of your actions. So beware of the beguilements of the world and those of women. The first trial of
        Banu Israel was through women". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) used
        to say: "Allahumma inni as'alukal-huda wat-tuqa wal-`afafa wal-ghina (O Allah! I ask You for guidance, piety,
        chastity and self-sufficiency)." [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Adi bin Hatim At-Ta'i (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: I heard the Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) say: "He who has taken an oath (to do something) but found something else better than that (which
        brings him closer to Allah), then he should do that which is better in piety (and he should expiate for the
        breaking of oath)". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Umamah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: I heard Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) during
        the sermon of the Farewell Pilgrimage saying, "Be mindful of your duty to Allah; perform your five daily Salat,
        observe Saum during the month (of Ramadan) , pay the Zakat on your properties and obey your leaders; (if you do
        so) you will enter the Jannah of your Rubb". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Abbas (رضي الله عنهما) reported that the Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) used to
        supplicate: "O Allah! To You I have submitted, and in You do I believe, and in You I put my trust, to You do I
        turn, and for You I argued. O Allah, I seek refuge with You through Your Power; there is none worthy of worship
        except You Alone; that You safeguard me against going astray. You are the Ever Living, the One Who sustains and
        protects all that exists; the One Who never dies, whereas human beings and jinn will all die." [Al-Bukhari and
        Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Abbas (رضي الله عنهما) said: When (Prophet) Ibrahim (Abraham) was thrown into the fire, he said: "Allah
        (Alone) is sufficient for us, and, He is the Best Disposer of affairs.'' So did Messenger of Allah Muhammad
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) when he was told: "A great army of the pagans had gathered against him, so
        fear them". But this (warning) only increased him and the Muslims in Faith and they said: "Allah (Alone) is
        sufficient for us, and He is the Best Disposer of affairs (for us)". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "A group of
        people (both men and women) whose hearts will be like the hearts of birds, will enter Jannah". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Umar (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: I heard Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) saying: "If
        you all depend on Allah with due reliance, He would certainly give you provision as He gives it to birds who go
        forth hungry in the morning and return with full belly at dusk". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Al-Bara' bin `Azib (رضي الله عنهما) said: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) asked me to
        recite whenever I go to bed: "Allahumma aslamtu nafsi ilaika, wa wajjahtu wajhi ilaika, wa fawwadtu amri ilaika,
        wal-ja'tu zahri ilaika, raghbatan wa rahbatan ilaika, la malja wa la manja minka illa ilaika. Amantu
        bikitabikal-ladhi anzalta, wa nabiyyikal-ladhi arsalta (O Allah! I have submitted myself to You, I have turned
        my face to You, entrusted my affairs to You; and committed my back to You out of desire for You and fear of You;
        expecting Your reward and fearing Your punishment). There is no refuge and no place of safety from You but with
        You. I believe in the Book You have revealed and in the Prophet You have sent.'' Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said that if anyone recited these words and died that night, he would die in the true
        religion. In case he remains alive till morning, he will obtain good. [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Bakr As-Siddiq (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: When Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) and
        I were in the cave of Thaur and I saw the feet of the polytheists who were above us at the mouth of the cave (on
        the eve of the Emigration), I submitted: "O Messenger of Allah! If one of them were to look down below his feet,
        he would see us". He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "O Abu Bakr! What do you think of two whose third
        is Allah". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Umm Salamah (رضي الله عنها) reported: Whenever the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) stepped out of
        his house, he would say, "Bismillah, tawakkaltu `alallah. Allahumma inni a`udhu bika an adilla aw udalla, aw
        azilla aw uzalla, aw azlima aw uzlama, aw ajhala aw yujhala `alayya". "[I go forth. (I begin with the Name of
        Allah, I trust in Allah; O Allah! I seek refuge in You from leaving or being led astray, or against slipping or
        being caused to slip; or doing injustice or being done injustice; or doing wrong or having wrong done to me)]".
        [Abu Dawud and At-Tirmidhi reported it. According to At-Tirmidhi, this Hadith is classified as Hasan Sahih. Its
        wording is from Abu Dawud].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Whoever
        says (upon leaving his house): `Bismillah, tawakkaltu `alallah, wa la hawla wa la quwwata illa billah [I begin
        with the Name of Allah; I trust in Allah; there is no altering of conditions but by the Power of Allah],' it
        will be said to him: 'You are guided, defended and protected.' The devil will go far away from him". [Abu Dawud,
        At-Tirmidhi and An-Nasa'i].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: There were two brothers in the days of the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ). One of them used to attend the Prophet's circle (to acquire knowledge) and the other used
        to earn their living). Once the latter complained to the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) against the
        former (for not earning his living). He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) replied, Perhaps you are being
        provided because of him. [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Sufyan bin `Abdullah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I said, O Messenger of Allah, tell me something of
        Islam which I will not ask anyone else about it.'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Say, `I believe
        in Allah' and then be steadfast". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Follow the Right Path of Faith strictly, and be steadfast; and keep in mind that none of you can achieve
        salvation through his (good) actions.'' Someone asked, "Not even you, O Messenger of Allah?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Not even me, unless Allah grants me His Mercy and Grace". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Be
        prompt in doing good deeds (before you are overtaken) by turbulence which would be like a part of the dark
        night. A man would be a believer in the morning and turn to disbelief in the evening, or he would be a believer
        in the evening and turn disbeliever in the morning, and would sell his Faith for worldly goods.'' [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Uqbah bin Al-Harith (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: Once I performed the 'Asr prayer in Al-Madinah behind the
        Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ). He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) got up quickly after finishing
        the prayer with Taslim, and stepping over the people, went to one of the rooms of his wives. The people were
        startled at his haste, and when he came out and saw their astonishment at his urgency he said, "I recalled that
        there was left with me some gold which was meant for charity; I did not like to keep it any longer, so I gave
        orders that it should be distributed". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: There came a man to the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        and said, "O Messenger of Allah, which charity is the most rewardable?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said, "That you should give charity (in a state when you are) healthy and stingy and fear poverty, hoping to
        become rich (charity in such a state of health and mind is the best). And you must not defer (charity to such a
        length) that you are about to die and would be saying: 'This is for so-and-so, and this for so-and-so.' Lo! It
        has already come into (the possession of) so-and-so". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Az-Zubair bin `Adi said: We went to Anas bin Malik (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) and complained to him of suffering
        at the hands of Al-Hajjaj. He replied: "Show endurance, for no time will come but will be followed by one worse
        (than the present one) till you meet your Rubb. I heard this from your Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ)". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Hasten to do good deeds before you are overtaken by one of the seven afflictions.'' Then (giving a warning) he
        said, "Are you waiting for such poverty which will make you unmindful of devotion; or prosperity which will make
        you corrupt, or disease as will disable you, or such senility as will make you mentally unstable, or sudden
        death, or Ad-Dajjal who is the worst expected absent, or the Hour, and the Hour will be most grievous and most
        bitter". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Allah the Exalted has said: 'I will declare war against him who shows hostility to a pious worshipper of Mine.
        And the most beloved thing with which My slave comes nearer to Me is what I have enjoined upon him; and My slave
        keeps on coming closer to Me through performing Nawafil (prayer or doing extra deeds besides what is obligatory)
        till I love him. When I love him I become his hearing with which he hears, his seeing with which he sees, his
        hand with which he strikes, and his leg with which he walks; and if he asks (something) from Me, I give him, and
        if he asks My Protection (refuge), I protect him". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Allah says: ' When
        a slave of Mine draws near to Me a span, I draw near to him a cubit; and if he draws near to Me a cubit, I draw
        near to him a fathom. And if he comes to Me walking, I go to him running.'''. [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn Abbas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "There
        are two blessings in which many people incur loss. (They are) health and free time (for doing good)".
        [Al-Bukhari]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (رضي الله عنها) said: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) would stand (in prayer) so long
        that the skin of his feet would crack. I asked him, "Why do you do this while your past and future sins have
        been forgiven?'' He said, "Should I not be a grateful slave of Allah?'' [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (رضي الله عنها) said: With the start of the last ten days of Ramadan, Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) would pray all the night, and would keep his family awake for the prayers. He tied his
        lower garment (i.e., avoided sleeping with his wives) and devoted himself entirely to prayer and supplication.
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "A
        strong believer is better and dearer to Allah than a weak one, and both are good. Adhere to that which is
        beneficial for you. Keep asking Allah for help and do not refrain from it. If you are afflicted in any way, do
        not say: `If I had taken this or that step, it would have resulted into such and such,' but say only: `Allah so
        determined and did as He willed.' The word `if' opens the gates of satanic thoughts". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said. "The
        (Hell) Fire is surrounded with all kinds of desires and passions, while Jannah is surrounded with adversities.''
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: One night I joined the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) in
        his (optional) Salat. He prolonged the standing so much that I thought of doing something evil. He was asked:
        "What did you intend to do?'' He replied: "To sit down and leave him". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Three
        follow a dead body: members of his family, his possessions and his deeds. Two of them return and one remains
        with him. His family and his possessions return; his deeds remain with him". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Jannah is
        nearer to anyone of you than your shoe-lace, and so is the (Hell) Fire". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Rabi`ah bin Ka`b Al-Aslami (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) (a servant of the Messenger of Allah and also one of the
        people of As-Suffah) said: I used to spend my night in the company of Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) and used to put up water for his ablutions. One day he said to me, "Ask something of me.'' I said: "I
        request for your companionship in Jannah". He inquired, "Is there anything else?'' I said, "That is all.'' He
        said, "Then help me in your request by multiplying your prostrations". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Thauban (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: I heard Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) saying,
        "Perform Salah more often. For every prostration that you perform before Allah will raise your position one
        degree and will remit one of your sins". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin Busr Al-Aslami (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The best of people is one whose life is long and his conduct is good". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Allah
        excuses and grants forgiveness to a person until he attains the age of sixty years". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        " Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: Allah the Rubb of honour and glory sent Revelation to His Messenger
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) more frequently before his death than at any other time. [Al-Bukhari and
        Muslim]. "
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, Every one will be
        raised in thecondition in which he dies". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Dharr (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I asked: "O Messenger of Allah! Which action is the best?'' He
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Faith in Allah and Jihad in the way of Allah.'' I asked: "Which neck
        (slave) is best (for emancipation)? He said, "That which is dearest of them in price and most valuable of them
        to its masters". I asked: If I cannot afford (it)?'' He said, Then help a labourer or work for one who is
        disabled". I asked: "If I cannot do (it)?'' He said, "You should restrain yourself from doing wrong to people,
        because it (serves as) charity which you bestow upon yourself". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Dharr (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "When
        you get up in the morning, charity is due from every one of your joints. There is charity in every ascription of
        glory to Allah; there is charity in every declaration of His Greatness; there is charity in every utterance of
        praise of Him; there is charity in every declaration that He is the only true God (worthy of worship); there is
        charity in enjoining good; there is charity in forbidding evil. Two Rak`ah of Duha (Forenoon prayer) is equal to
        all this (in reward)". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Dharr (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The deeds of
        my people, good and bad, were presented before me, and I found the removal of harmful objects from the road
        among their good deeds, and phlegm which might be in a mosque left unburied among their evil deeds". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Dharr (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Some people said to Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ): "O Messenger of Allah, the rich have taken away (all the) reward. They observe Salat (prayers) as we
        do; and give Sadaqah (charity) out of their surplus wealth.'' Upon this he (the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ)) said, "Has Allah not prescribed for you (a course) following which you can (also) give Sadaqah? In
        every declaration of the glorification of Allah (i.e., saying Subhan Allah) there is a Sadaqah, and in every
        Takbir (i.e., saying Allahu Akbar) is a Sadaqah, and in every celebration of praise (saying Al-hamdu lillah) is
        a Sadaqah, and in every declaration that He is One (La ilaha illallah) is a Sadaqah, and in enjoining of good is
        a Sadaqah, and in forbidding evil is a Sadaqah, and in man's sexual intercourse (with his wife) there is a
        Sadaqah.'' They (the Companions) said: "O Messenger of Allah, is there reward for him who satisfies his sexual
        need among us?'' He said, "You see, if he were to satisfy it with something forbidden, would it not be a sin on
        his part? Similarly, if he were to satisfy it legally, he should be rewarded". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Dharr (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Do not
        belittle any good deed, even meeting your brother (Muslim) with a cheerful face". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Every day the sun rises charity (Sadaqah) is due on every joint of a person: you administer justice between two
        men is a charity; and assisting a man to mount his beast, or helping him load his luggage on it is a charity;
        and a good word is a charity; and every step that you take (towards the mosque) for Salat (prayer) is a charity
        and removing harmful things from the road is a charity". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "He who
        goes to the mosque at dawn or dusk (for Salat), Allah prepares a hospitable abode for him in Jannah, every time
        when he walks to it or comes back from it". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: O Muslim women, never belittle any gift you give your neighbour
        even if it is a hoof of a sheep". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ): The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Iman has over
        seventy branches, the uppermost of which is the declaration: `None has the right to be worshipped but Allah';
        and the least of which is the removal of harmful object from the road, and modesty is a branch of Iman.''
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "While a man was walking on his way he became extremely thirsty. He found a well, he went down into it to drink
        water. Upon leaving it, he saw a dog which was panting out of thirst. His tongue was lolling out and he was
        eating moist earth from extreme thirst. The man thought to himself: `This dog is extremely thirsty as I was.' So
        he descended into the well, filled up his leather sock with water, and holding it in his teeth, climbed up and
        quenched the thirst of the dog. Allah appreciated his action and forgave his sins". The Companions asked: "Shall
        we be rewarded for showing kindness to the animals also?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "A reward
        is given in connection with every living creature". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]. In the narration of Al-Bukhari, the
        Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) is reported to have said: "Allah forgave him in appreciation of this
        act and admitted him to Jannah". Another narration says: "Once a dog was going round the well and was about to
        die out of thirst. A prostitute of Banu Israel happened to see it. So she took off her leather sock and lowered
        it into the well. She drew out some water and gave the dog to drink. She was forgiven on account of her action".
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "He
        who performs his Wudu' perfectly and comes to Jumu`ah prayer and listens (to the Khutbah) silently, the sins
        which he has committed since the previous Friday plus three more days (i.e., 10 days) will be forgiven for him.
        One who distracts himself with pebbles during the Khutbah will not get the (Jumu`ah) reward". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "When a Muslim or a believer washes his face (in the course of Wudu'), every sin he has committed with his eyes
        is washed away from his face along with water, or with the last drop of water; when he washes his hands, every
        sin they wrought is erased from his hands with the water, or with the last drop of water; and when he washes his
        feet, every sin towards which his feet walked is washed away with water, or with the last drop of water, with
        the result that he comes out cleansed of all sins". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The
        five (daily) Salat (prayers), and from one Jumu`ah prayer to the (next) Jumu`ah prayer, and from Ramadan to
        Ramadan are expiations for the (sins) committed in between (their intervals); provided the major sins are not
        committed". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Should I not direct you to something by which Allah obliterates the sins and elevates (your) ranks.'' They
        said: "Yes, O Messenger of Allah". He said, "Performing Wudu' properly, even in difficulty, frequently going to
        the mosque, and waiting eagerly for the next Salat (prayer) after a Salat is over; indeed, that is Ar-Ribat".
        [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa Al-Ash`ari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said, "He who observes the Fajr and `Asr (prayers) will enter Jannah.'' [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa Al-Ash`ari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said, "When a slave of Allah suffers from illness or sets on a journey, he is credited with the equal of
        whatever good works he used to do when he was healthy or at home". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that he heard Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        saying, "Every good deed is charity". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "When a
        Muslim plants a tree, whatever is eaten from it is charity from him and whatever is stolen is charity and
        whatever is subtracted from it is charity". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The tribe Banu Salimah wanted to move nearer to the mosque. On
        learning this Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said to them, "I heard that you intend to
        move nearer to the mosque". They said, "That is so, O Messenger of Allah, we do want to do that". He said, "O
        Banu Salimah, keep to your homes, your steps (to the mosque) are recorded". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ubayy bin Ka`b (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: There was a man, and I do not know of any other man whose
        house was farther than his from the mosque, and he never missed Salat (in congregation). It was said to him (or
        I said to him): "If you buy a donkey you could ride it in the dark nights and in the burning sand.'' He said: "I
        do not like my house to be by the side of the mosque, for I (eagerly) desire that my steps towards the mosque
        and back from it should be recorded when I return to my family.'' Upon this Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Allah has granted you all the rewards for you". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Allah will
        be pleased with His slave who praises Him (i.e., says Al-hamdu lillah) when he eats and praises Him when he
        drinks". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa Al-Ash`ari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Giving in charity is an obligation upon every Muslim". It was said (to him): "What about one who does not find
        (the means) to do so?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Let him work with his hands, thus doing
        benefit to himself and give in charity.'' It was said to him: "What if he does not have (the means) to do so?''
        He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Then let him assist the needy, the aggrieved.'' It was said: "What
        about if he cannot even do this?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Then he should enjoin good.'' He
        was asked: "What if he cannot do that?'' He (the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)) said, "He should
        then abstain from evil, for verily, that is a charity from him". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Aishah (رضي الله عنها) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) came in when a woman was
        sitting beside me. He asked me, "Who is she?'' I said: "She is the one whose performance of Salat (prayer) has
        become the talk of the town.'' Addressing her, he (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "(What is this!) You
        are required to take upon yourselves only what you can carry out easily. By Allah, Allah does not withhold His
        Mercy and forgiveness of you until you neglect and give up (good works). Allah likes the deeds best which a
        worshipper can carry out constantly". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Three men came to the houses of the wives of the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) to inquire about the worship of the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ). When they
        were informed, they considered their worship insignificant and said: "Where are we in comparison with the
        Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) while Allah has forgiven his past sins and future sins". One of them
        said: "As for me, I shall offer Salat all night long.'' Another said: "I shall observe Saum (fasting)
        continuously and shall not break it". Another said: "I shall abstain from women and shall never marry". The
        Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) came to them and said, "Are you the people who said such and such
        things? By Allah, I fear Allah more than you do, and I am most obedient and dutiful among you to Him, but still
        I observe fast and break it; perform Salat and sleep at night and take wives. So whoever turns away from my
        Sunnah does not belong to me". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Ruined are
        those who insist on hardship in matters of the Faith.'' He repeated this three times. [Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The
        religion (of Islam) is easy, and whoever makes the religion a rigour, it will overpower him. So, follow a middle
        course (in worship); if you can't do this, do something near to it and give glad tidings and seek help (of
        Allah) at morn and at dusk and some part of night". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) came into the mosque and
        noticed a rope stretched between two poles. He enquired, "What is this rope for?'' He was told: "This is
        Zainab's rope. When during her voluntary prayer, she begins to feel tired, she grasps it for support". The
        Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Untie it. You should perform prayers so long as you feel
        active. When you feel tired, you should go to sleep". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (رضي الله عنها) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "When one of
        you feels drowsy during prayer, let him lie down till drowsiness goes away from him, because when one of you
        performs prayers while feeling sleepy, he does not know whether he seeks forgiveness or abuses himself".
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir bin Samurah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I used to perform prayer with the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) and his Salat was of a moderate length and his Khutbah too was moderate in length. [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Abbas (رضي الله عنهما) reported: While the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) was delivering
        Khutbah (religious talk), he noticed a man who was standing, so he asked about him and was told that he was Abu
        Israel who had taken a vow to remain standing and not sit, or go into the shade, or speak while observing
        fasting. Thereupon Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "Tell him to speak, to go into
        the shade, to sit and to complete his fast''. [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Umar bin Al-Khattab (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Should anyone fall asleep at night and fail to recite his portion of the Qur'an, or a part of it, if he
        recites it between the Fajr prayer and the Zuhr prayer, it will be recorded for him as though he had recited it
        during the night''. [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin `Amr bin Al-`as (رضي الله عنهما) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ
        ) said to me, "O Abdullah! Do not be like so-and-so. He used to get up at night for optional prayer but
        abandoned it later.'' [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (رضي الله عنها) reported: When Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) missed the
        optional night Salat (Tahajjud) due to pain or any other reason, he would perform twelve Rak`ah during the day
        time. [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "Do not
        ask me unnecessarily about the details of the things which I do not mention to you. Verily, the people before
        you were doomed because they were used to putting many questions to their Prophets and had differences about
        their Prophets. Refrain from what I forbid you and do what I command you to the best of your ability and
        capacity". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Irbad bin Sariyah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: One day Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) delivered us a very eloquent Khutbah on account of which eyes shed tears and hearts were full of
        tears. A man said: "O Prophet of Allah, this is as if it were a parting advice. So advise us". He (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "I admonish you to fear Allah, to listen and obey even if an Abyssinian slave is
        appointed as your leader. Because whosoever among you shall live after me, will see much discord. So hold fast
        to my Sunnah and the examples of the Rightly-Guided Caliphs who will come after me. Adhere to them and hold to
        it fast. Beware of new things (in Deen) because every Bid`ah is a misguidance". [Abu Dawud and At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "Everyone of my Ummah will enter Jannah except those who refuse". He was asked: "Who will refuse?'' He (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "Whoever obeys me, shall enter Jannah, and whosoever disobeys me, refuses to
        (enter Jannah)". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Salamah bin Al-Akwa` (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: My father said that a person ate in the presence of
        Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) with his left hand. He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Eat with your right hand". He said, "I cannot do that.'' Thereupon he (the Prophet) said, "May you never
        do that.'' It was pride that prevented him from doing it. And he could not raise it (the right hand) up to his
        mouth afterwards. [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Nu`man bin Bashir (رضي الله عنهما) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "Straighten your rows (during Salat) or Allah would create dissension amongst you". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]. In
        another narration reported by Muslim, Nu`man bin Bashir (رضي الله عنهما) narrated: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) used to straighten our rows (in Salat), as if he was straightening an arrow with
        their help until he saw that we had learnt it from him. One day he came out, stood up (for Salat) and was about
        to say: Allahu Akbar (Allah is the Greatest), (marking the beginning of the prayer) when he saw a man, whose
        chest was bulging out from the row. He said, "Slaves of Allah, you must straighten your rows or Allah would
        create dissension amongst you.''
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: A house in Al-Madinah caught fire at night and the roof and walls
        fell down upon the occupants. When this was reported to Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) he
        said, "Fire is your enemy; so put it out before you go to bed". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "The
        similitude of guidance and knowledge with which Allah has sent me is like a rain which has fallen on some
        ground. A fertile part of earth has absorbed water and brought forth much grass and herbs. Another part, which
        is solid, held the water and Allah benefits men thereby, who drank and gave others to drink, and used it for
        irrigation. But some of it has fallen on a portion of sandy land which neither retains the water nor produces
        herbage. Such is the likeness of the man who understands the religion of Allah and who gets benefit of what
        Allah has sent me with; he learns and teaches others. It is also the likeness of the man who neither raises his
        head on that account (meaning he does not benefit from what the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) was
        sent with) nor accepts Allah's Guidance with which I am sent". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "My
        parable and that of yours is like a man who kindled a fire. When it has illuminated all around him, the moths
        and grasshoppers began to fall therein. He tried to push them away, but they overcame him and jumped into it. I
        am catching hold of your waists ties (to save you) from fire, but you slip away from my hands". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) commanded the
        licking of fingers (after eating) and the cleaning of the dish, saying: "You do not know in what portion the
        Blessing (of Allah) lies". [Muslim]. In another narration, Jabir said: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "When a morsel of any of you falls down, you should pick it up and remove any dirt or dust on
        it and then eat it; and don't leave it for Satan; and do not wipe your hand with the towel until you have licked
        your fingers, for you do not know in what portion of the food the Barakah* (of Allah) lies".* Barakah is the
        abundance of goodness and its continuity.
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Abbas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "On
        the Day of Resurrection you will be assembled barefooted, naked and uncircumcised". He then recited: "As We
        began the first creation, We shall repeat it. (It is) a promise binding upon Us. Truly, We shall do it,'' and
        continued: "The first to be clothed on the Day of Resurrection will be (Prophet) Ibrahim. Then some of my
        Companions will be taken to the left, (i.e., towards Hell-fire) and when I will say, 'They belong to my Ummah, O
        my Rubb!' It would be said: 'You do not know what they invented after you had left them.' I shall then say as
        the righteous slave [i.e., `Isa (Jesus (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )] said: 'And I was a witness over them
        while I was amongst them, when You took me up, You were the Watcher over them and You are a Witness to all
        things. If you punish them, they are Your slaves, and if You forgive them, verily, You, only You are the
        All-Mighty, the All-Wise.' I shall be told: 'They continued to turn on their heels since you parted from them".
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin Mughaffal (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ
        ) prohibited flicking pebbles by the index finger and the thumb; and he said, "It does not kill a game animal
        nor does it inflict wound on the enemy, but breaks the tooth and gorges the eye". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]. In
        another narration it is said: A close relative of `Abdullah bin Mughaffal (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) was hitting with
        pebbles using the index finger and the thumb; he said: "Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        has forbidden it saying that it does not kill the game". He repeated the act and Ibn Mughaffal said to him: "I
        told you that the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) had prohibited it but you repeated it. I shall
        never talk to you.''
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abis bin Rabi`ah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I saw `Umar bin Al-Khattab(May Allah be pleased with him)
        kissing the Black Stone (Al-Hajar Al-Aswad) and saying: "I know that you are just a stone and that you can
        neither do any harm nor give benefit. Had I not seen Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        kissing you, I would not have kissed you". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (رضي الله عنها) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "If anyone
        introduces in our matter something which does not belong to it, will be rejected". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]. The
        narration in Muslim says: "If anybody introduces a practice which is not authenticated by me, it is to be
        rejected".
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Whenever the Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        delivered a Khutbah, his eyes would become red, his tone loud and he showed anger as if he were warning us
        against an army. He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) would say, "The enemy is about to attack you in the
        morning and the enemy is advancing against you in the evening". He would further say, "I am sent with the final
        Hour like these two fingers of mine.'' Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) held up his index
        finger and the middle finger together to illustrate. He used to add: "To proceed, the best speech is the Book of
        Allah and the best guidance is the guidance of Muhammad (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ), the worst practice
        is the introduction of new practices in Islam and every Bid`ah is a misguidance". He would also say, "I am, in
        respect of rights, nearer to every believer than his own self. He who leaves an estate, it belongs to his heirs,
        and he who leaves a debt, it is my responsibility to pay it off.'' [Muslim]. Same Hadith as reported by `Irbad
        bin Sariyah (May Allah be pleased with him) has already been recorded in the previous chapter regarding
        safeguarding the Sunnah of the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ).
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "The first
        son of Adam* takes a share of the guilt of every one who murders another wrongfully because he was the initiator
        of committing murder". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        "Abu Mas`ud `Uqbah bin `Amr Al-Ansari Al-Badri (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, Whoever guides someone to virtue will be rewarded equivalent to him who
        practices that good" action". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "If
        anyone calls others to follow right guidance, his reward will be equivalent to those who follow him (in
        righteousness) without their reward being diminished in any respect, and if anyone invites others to follow
        error, the sin, will be equivalent to that of the people who follow him (in sinfulness) without their sins being
        diminished in any respect". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas bin Malik (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: A young man from the tribe of Aslam said, "O Messenger of
        Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ), I wish to fight (in the Cause of Allah) but I do not have anything to
        equip myself with (for fighting)". He (the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )) said, "Go to so-and-so,
        for he had equipped himself (for fighting) but he fell ill.'' So he (the young man) went to him and said,
        "Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) sends you his greetings and says that you should give me
        the equipment that you have provided yourself with.'' The man said (to his wife or servant): "O so-and-so, give
        him the equipment I have collected for myself and do not withhold anything from him. By Allah, if you withhold
        anything from him, we will not be blessed therein." [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Khalid Al-Juhani (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "He
        who equips a warrior in the way of Allah (will get the reward of the one who has actually gone for Jihad); and
        he who looks after the family of a warrior in the way of Allah will get the reward of the one who has gone for
        Jihad". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sa`id Al-Khudri (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        sent a detachment to Banu Lahyan tribe and remarked, "Let one of every two men get ready to advance, and both
        will earn the same reward". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Abbas (رضي الله عنهما) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) came across a
        party of mounted men at Ar-Rauha and asked them, "Who are you?'' They answered: "We are Muslims, and who are
        you?'' He said, "I am the Messenger of Allah.'' A woman from among them lifted a boy up to him and asked: "Can
        this one go on Hajj?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "Yes, and you will have the reward.''
        [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "The honest
        Muslim trustee who carries out duties assigned to him (in another narration he said, "Who gives''), and he gives
        that in full, with his heart overflowing with cheerfulness, to whom he is ordered, he is one of the two givers
        of charity". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Tamim bin Aus Ad-Dari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "Ad-Deen is sincerity". We said: "For whom?'' He replied, "For Allah, His Book, His Messenger and for the
        leaders of the Muslims and their masses". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jarir bin `Abdullah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I made my covenant with Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) on the observance of Salat, payment of Zakat, and giving counsel to Muslim.'' [Al-Bukhari
        and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "No one of you
        becomes a true believer until he likes for his brother what he likes for himself". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sa`id Al-Khudri (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Whoever amongst you sees an evil, he must change it with his hand; if he is unable to do so, then with
        his tongue; and if he is unable to do so, then with his heart; and that is the weakest form of Faith". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abdullah bin Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Never a Prophet had been sent before me by Allah to his people but he had, among his people, (his)
        disciples and companions, who followed his ways and obeyed his command. Then there came after them their
        successors who proclaimed what they did not practise, and practised what they were not commanded to do. And (he)
        who strove against them with his hand is a believer; he who strove against them with his heart is a believer;
        and he who strove against them with his tongue is a believer ; and beyond that there is no grain of Faith".
        [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Ubadah bin As-Samit (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: We swore allegiance to Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) to hear and obey; in time of difficulty and in prosperity, in hardship and in ease, to
        endure being discriminated against and not to dispute about rule with those in power, except in case of evident
        infidelity regarding which there is a proof from Allah. We swore allegiance to Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) to say what was right wherever we were, and not to fear from anyone's reproach. [Al-Bukhari
        and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Nu`man bin Bashir (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "The
        likeness of the man who observes the limits prescribed by Allah and that of the man who transgresses them is
        like the people who get on board a ship after casting lots. Some of them are in its lower deck and some of them
        in its upper (deck). Those who are in its lower (deck), when they require water, go to the occupants of the
        upper deck, and say to them : `If we make a hole in the bottom of the ship, we shall not harm you.' If they (the
        occupants of the upper deck) leave them to carry out their design they all will be drowned. But if they do not
        let them go ahead (with their plan), all of them will remain safe". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Umm Salamah (رضي الله عنها) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "You will have
        rulers some of whom you approve and some of whom you will disapprove. He who dislikes them will be safe, and he
        who expresses disapproval will be safe, but he who is pleased and follows them (will be indeed sinful)". His
        audience asked: "Shall we not fight them?'' He replied, "No, as long as they establish Salat amongst you".
        [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Zainab (رضي الله عنها) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) came to visit me one day
        frightened and he ü said, "La ilaha illallah (There is no true God but Allah). Woe to the Arabs because of an
        evil which has drawn near! Today an opening of this size has been made in the barrier restraining Ya'juj and
        Ma'juj (Gog and Magog people).'' And he (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) made a circle with his thumb and
        index finger. I said, ``O Messenger of Allah! Shall we perish while still there will be righteous people among
        us?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) replied, ``Yes, when wickedness prevails". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sa`id Al-Khudri (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "Beware of sitting on roads (ways).'' The people said: "We have but them as sitting places.'' Messenger of Allah
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "If you have to sit there, then observe the rights of the way". They
        asked, "What are the rights of the way?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "To lower your gaze (on
        seeing what is illegal to look at), and (removal of harmful objects), returning greetings, enjoining good and
        forbidding wrong". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin `Abbas (رضي الله عنهما) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) saw a
        man wearing a gold ring. So he (the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )) pulled it off and threw it away,
        saying, "One of you takes a live coal, and puts it on his hand.'' It was said to the man after Messenger of
        Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) had left: "Take your ring (of gold) and utilize it,'' whereupon he
        said: "No, by Allah, I would never take it when Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) has thrown
        it away". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sa`id Al-Hasan Basri reported: `Aidh bin `Amr (the Companion) (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) visited `Ubaidullah
        bin Ziyad (the ruler) and said to him: "Son, I heard Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        saying, `The worst shepherds (rulers) are those who deal harshly in respect of supervision. Beware, Don't be one
        of them!''' Ibn Ziyad said to him, "Sit down, you are but husk from among the Companions of the Prophet (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ).'' `Aidh bin `Amr (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) retorted: "Was there any husk among them?
        Surely, husk came after them and among others than them". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Hudhaifah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "By
        Him in Whose Hand my life is, you either enjoin good and forbid evil, or Allah will certainly soon send His
        punishment to you. Then you will make supplication and it will not be accepted". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Sa`id Al-Khudri (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "The best type of Jihad (striving in the way of Allah) is speaking a true word in the presence of a tyrant
        ruler.'' [Abu Dawud and At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu `Abdullah Tariq bin Shihab (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: A person asked the Prophet (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) (when he had just put his foot in the stirrup): "What is the highest form of Jihad?''
        He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, Speaking the truth in the presence of a tyrant ruler. [An-Nasa'i].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Bakr As-Siddiq (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: "O you people! You recite this Verse: `O you who
        believe! Take care of your ownselves. If you follow the (right) guidance [and enjoin what is right (Islamic
        Monotheism and all that Islam orders one to do) and forbid what is wrong (polytheism, disbelief and all that
        Islam has forbidden)] no hurt can come to you from those who are in error.' (5:105) But I have heard Messenger
        of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) saying: "When people see an oppressor but do not prevent him from
        (doing evil), it is likely that Allah will punish them all.'' [Abu Dawud and At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Usamah bin Zaid (May Allah bepleased with them) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) said, A man will be brought on the Day of Resurrection and will be cast into Hell, and his
        intestines will pour forth and he will go round them as a donkey goes round a millstone. The inmates of Hell
        will gather round him and say: `What has happened to you, O so-and-so? Were you not enjoining us to do good and
        forbidding us to do evil?' He will reply: `I was enjoining you to do good, but was not doing it myself; and I
        was forbidding you to do evil, but was doing it myself". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jabir bin `Abdullah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "Beware of injustice, for oppression will be darkness on the Day of Resurrection; and beware
        of stinginess because it doomed those who were before you. It incited them to shed blood and treat the unlawful
        as lawful.'' [Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "On the Resurrection Day, the rights will be paid to those to whom they are due so much so that a hornless
        sheep will be retaliated for by punishing the horned sheep which broke its horns". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Umar (May Allah bepleased with them) reported: We were talking about the Farewell Pilgrimage without
        knowing what was it when Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) was also present. He (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) stood up and recited the Praise and Glorification of Allah. He then gave a detailed
        account of Ad-Dajjal and said, 'Every Prophet sent by Allah had warned his people against his mischief. Nuh
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) )warned his nation and so did all the Prophets after him. If he (i.e.,
        Ad-Dajjal) appears among you, his condition will not remain hidden from you. Your Rubb is not one-eyed, but
        Ad-Dajjal is. His right eye is protruding like a swollen grape. Listen, Allah has made your blood, and your
        properties as inviolable as of this day of yours (i.e., the Day of Sacrifice), in this city of yours (i.e.,
        Makkah), in this month of yours (i.e., Dhul -Hijjah). Listen, have I conveyed Allah's Message to you?'' The
        people replied in affirmative. There upon he said, "O Allah, bear witness.'' And he repeated it thrice. He
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) concluded: "Do not revert after me as infidels killing one another".
        [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (May Allah bepleased with her) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "Whoever usurps unlawfully even a hand span of land a collar measuring seven times (this) land will be placed
        around his neck on the Day of Resurrection". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Verily, Allah gives respite to the oppressor. But when He seizes him, He does not let him escape.'' Then
        he (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )) recited, "Such is the Seizure of your Rubb when He seizes the (population
        of) towns while they are doing wrong. Verily, His Seizure is painful (and) severe". (11:102). [Al-Bukhari and
        Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Mu`adh (May Allah bepleased with him) reported that Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        sent me (as a governor of Yemen) and instructed me thus: "You will go to the people of the Book. First call them
        to testify that `there is no true god except Allah, that I am (Muhammad (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )) the
        Messenger of Allah.' If they obey you, tell them that Allah has enjoined upon them five Salat (prayers) during
        the day and night; and if they obey you, inform them that Allah has made Zakat obligatory upon them; that it
        should be collected from their rich and distributed among their poor; and if they obey you refrain from picking
        up (as a share of Zakat) the best of their wealth. Beware of the supplication of the oppressed, for there is no
        barrier between it and Allah". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Humaid bin Sa`d As-Sa`idi (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) employed a man from the tribe of Al-Azd named Ibn Lutbiyyah as collector of Zakat. When the employee
        returned (with the collections) he said: "(O Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )!) This is for you and
        this is mine because it was presented to me as gift.'' Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        rose to the pulpit and praised Allah and extolled Him. Then he said, "I employ a man to do a job and he comes
        and says: `This is for you and this has been presented to me as gift'? Why did he not remain in the house of his
        father or the house of his mother and see whether gifts will be given to him or not? By Allah in Whose Hand is
        the life of Muhammad, if any one of you took anything wrongfully, he will bring it on the Day of Resurrection,
        carrying it on (his back), I will not recognize anyone of you, on the Day of Resurrection with a grunting camel,
        or a bellowing cow, or a bleating ewe.'' Then he raised his hands till we could see the whiteness of his
        armpits. Then he said thrice, ``O Allah ! have I conveyed (Your Commandments)''. [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "He who has done a wrong affecting his brother's honour or anything else, let him ask his forgiveness today
        before the time (i.e., the Day of Resurrection) when he will have neither a dinar nor a dirham. If he has done
        some good deeds, a portion equal to his wrong doings will be subtracted from them; but if he has no good deeds,
        he will be burdened with the evil deeds of the one he had wronged in the same proportion". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Muslim is the one from whose tongue and hands the Muslims are safe; and a Muhajir (Emigrant) is the one who
        refrains from what Allah has forbidden". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Abdullah bin `Amr bin Al-`as (May Allah bepleased with them) reported: A man named Kirkirah, who was in
        charge of the personal effects of Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) passed away and the
        Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "He is in the (Hell) Fire.'' Some people went to his house
        looking for its cause and found there a cloak that he had stolen. [Al- Bukhari]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Umamah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Allah decrees the (Hell) Fire and debars Jannah for the one who usurps the rights of a believer by taking
        a false oath.'' One man asked: O Messenger of Allah! Even if it should be for an insignificant thing?'' He said,
        Even if it be a stick of the Arak tree (i.e., the tree from which Miswak sticks are taken)". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Adi bin `Umairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "Whosoever among you is appointed by us to a position and he conceals from us even a needle or
        less, it will amount to misappropriation and he will be called upon to restore it on the Day of Resurrection".
        (`Adi bin `Umairah added:) A black man from the Ansar stood up - I can see him still - and said: "O Messenger of
        Allah, take back from me your assignment.'' He (the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )) said, "What has
        happened to you?'' The man replied: "I have heard you saying such and such.'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "I say that even now: Whosoever from you is appointed by us to a position, he should render an
        account of everything, big or small, and whatever he is given therefrom, he should take and he should desist
        from taking what is unlawful". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Umar bin Al-Khattab (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: On the day (of the battle) of Khaibar, some
        Companions of the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) came and remarked: "So-and-so is a martyr and
        so-and-so is a martyr". When they came to a man about whom they said: "So-and-so is a martyr,'' the Prophet
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) declared, "No. I have seen him in Hell for a mantle (or cloak) which he has
        stolen". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Qatadah Al-Harith bin Rib`i (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, Faith in Allah and striving in His Cause (Jihad) are the deeds of highest merit.'' A
        man stood up said: O Messenger of Allah! Tell me if I am killed in the Cause of Allah, will all my sins be
        forgiven?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) replied, "Yes, if you are killed in the Cause of Allah while
        you are patient, hopeful of your reward and marching forward not retreating." Then the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said to him, "Repeat what you have said.'' The man said: "Tell me if I am killed in the
        Cause of Allah, will all my sins be remitted?". He replied, "Yes, if you are martyred while you are patient,
        hopeful of your reward and march forward without retreating, unless, if you owe any debt, that will not be
        remitted. Angel Jibril told me that". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Do you know who is the bankrupt?'' They said: "The bankrupt among us is one who has neither money with
        him nor any property". He said, "The real bankrupt of my Ummah would be he who would come on the Day of
        Resurrection with Salat, Saum and Sadaqah (charity), (but he will find himself bankrupt on that day as he will
        have exhausted the good deeds) because he reviled others, brought calumny against others, unlawfully devoured
        the wealth of others, shed the blood of others and beat others; so his good deeds would be credited to the
        account of those (who suffered at his hand). If his good deeds fall short to clear the account, their sins would
        be entered in his account and he would be thrown in the (Hell) Fire". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Umm Salamah (May Allah bepleased with her) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Verily, I am only a human and the claimants bring to me (their disputes); perhaps some of them are more
        eloquent than others. I judge according to what I hear from them). So, he whom I, by my judgment, (give the
        undue share) out of the right of a Muslim, I in fact give him a portion of (Hell) Fire". [Al-Bukhari and
        Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Umar (May Allah bepleased with them) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "A believer continues to guard his Faith (and thus hopes for Allah's Mercy) so long as he does not shed
        blood unjustly". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Khaulah bint `Thamir (May Allah bepleased with her) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "Many people misappropriate (acquire wrongfully) Allah's Property (meaning Muslims' property).
        These people will be cast in Hell on the Day of Resurrection". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "The relationship of the believer with another believer is like (the bricks of) a building, each
        strengthens the other.'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) illustrated this by interlacing the fingers of
        both his hands. [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Musa (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Whoever enters our mosque or passes through our market with arrows with him, he should hold them by their
        heads lest it should injure any of the Muslims". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Nu`man bin Bashir (May Allah bepleased with them) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "The believers in their mutual kindness, compassion and sympathy are just like one body. When
        one of the limbs suffers, the whole body responds to it with wakefulness and fever". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) kissed
        his grandson Al-Hasan bin `Ali (May Allah bepleased with them) in the presence of Al-Aqra` bin Habis. Thereupon
        he remarked: "I have ten children and I have never kissed any one of them.'' Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) looked at him and said, "He who does not show mercy to others will not be shown mercy".
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (May Allah bepleased with her) reported: Some bedouins came to Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) and asked: "Do you kiss your children?'' He said, "Yes". They then said: "By Allah, we do
        not kiss them.'' The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) replied, "I cannot help you if Allah has
        snatched kindness from your hearts". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jarir bin `Abdullah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "He who is not merciful to people Allah will not be merciful to him.'' [Al-Bukhari and
        Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "When one of you leads the Salat, he should not prolong it because the congregation includes those who are
        feeble, ill or old". One version adds: "those who have to attend to work'') While offering prayers alone, you
        may pray as long as you like". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (May Allah bepleased with her) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) would
        sometimes abstain from doing something he wished to do, lest others should follow him and it might become
        obligatory upon them. [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (May Allah bepleased with her) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) prohibited
        his Companions out of mercy for them, from observing continuous fasting without a break. They said: "But you
        observe fast continuously". He replied, "I am not like you. I spend the night while my Rubb provides me with
        food and drink". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Qatadah Al-Harith bin Rib`i (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "I stand up to lead Salat with the intention of prolonging it. Then I hear the crying
        of an infant and I shorten the Salat lest I should make it burdensome for his mother." [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Jundub bin Abdullah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "When anyone offers the Fajr (dawn) prayer, in congregation, he is in the Protection of Allah. So let not
        Allah call him to account, withdrawing, in any respect, His Protection. Because, He will get hold of him and
        throw him down on his face in the Hell-fire.'' [Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Umar (May Allah bepleased with them) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "A Muslim is a brother of another Muslim. So he should not oppress him nor should he hand him over to (his
        satan or to his self which is inclined to evil). Whoever fulfills the needs of his brother, Allah will fulfill
        his needs; whoever removes the troubles of his brother, Allah will remove one of his troubles on the Day of
        Resurrection; and whoever covers up the fault of a Muslim, Allah will cover up his fault on the Day of
        Resurrection". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "A Muslim is a brother to a Muslim. He should neither deceive him nor lie to him, nor leave him without
        assistance. Everything belonging to a Muslim is inviolable for a Muslim; his honour, his blood and property.
        Piety is here (and he pointed out to his chest thrice). It is enough for a Muslim to commit evil by despising
        his Muslim brother.'' [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "Do not envy one another; do not inflate prices by overbidding against one another; do not hate one
        another; do not harbour malice against one another; and do not enter into commercial transaction when others
        have entered into that (transaction); but be you, O slaves of Allah, as brothers. A Muslim is the brother of
        another Muslim; he neither oppresses him nor does he look down upon him, nor does he humiliate him. Piety is
        here, (and he pointed to his chest three times). It is enough evil for a Muslim to hold his brother Muslim in
        contempt. All things of a Muslim are inviolable for his brother-in-faith: his blood, his property and his
        honour". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "No one
        of you shall become a true believer until he desires for his brother what he desires for himself". [Al-Bukhari
        and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Anas (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "Help your brother, whether he is an oppressor or is oppressed". A man enquired: "O Messenger of Allah! I help
        him when he is oppressed, but how can I help him when he is an oppressor?'' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ
        ) said, "You can keep him from committing oppression. That will be your help to him". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "A believer owes another believer five rights: responding to greetings, visiting him in illness, following
        his funeral, accepting his invitation, and saying `Yarhamuk-Allah (May Allah have mercy on you),' when he says
        `Al-hamdu lillah (Praise be to Allah)' after sneezing". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Al-Bara' bin `Azib (May Allah bepleased with them) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        commanded us to observe seven things and forbade us seven. He ordered us to visit the sick; to follow funeral
        processions; to respond to a sneezer with `Yarhamuk-Allah (May Allah have mercy on you)' when he says `Al-hamdu
        lillah (Praise be to Allah),' to help the oppressed and to help others to fulfill their oaths, to accept
        invitation and to promote greeting. He forbade us to wear gold rings, to drink in silver utensils, to use
        Mayathir (silk carpets placed on saddles), to wear Al- Qassiy (a kind of silk cloth) to wear fine silk brocade.
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, Allah will
        cover up on the Day of Resurrection the defects (faults) of the one who covers up the faults of the others in
        this world". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "Every one of my followers will be forgiven except those who expose (openly) their wrongdoings. An example of
        this is that of a man who commits a sin at night which Allah has covered for him, and in the morning, he would
        say (to people): "I committed such and such sin last night,' while Allah had kept it a secret. During the night
        Allah has covered it up but in the morning he tears up the cover provided by Allah Himself.'' [Al-Bukhari and
        Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "When a slave-girl commits fornication and this fact of fornication has become evident, she must be given the
        penalty of (fifty) lashes without hurling reproaches at her; if she does it again, she must be given the penalty
        but she should not be rebuked. If she does it for the third time, he should sell her, even for a rope woven from
        hair (i.e., something worthless)". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: A man who had drunk wine was brought to the Prophet
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) and he asked us to beat him; some struck him with their hands, some with
        their garments (making a whip) and some with their sandals. When he (the drunkard) had gone, some of the people
        said: "May Allah disgrace you!'' He (the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )) said, "Do not say so. Do
        not help the devil against him". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Umar (May Allah bepleased with them) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, "A Muslim is a brother of (another) Muslim, he neither wrongs him nor does hand him over to one who does
        him wrong. If anyone fulfills his brother's needs, Allah will fulfill his needs; if one relieves a Muslim of his
        troubles, Allah will relieve his troubles on the Day of Resurrection; and if anyone covers up a Muslim (his
        sins), Allah will cover him up (his sins) on the Resurrection Day". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (May Allah bepleased with him) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said,
        "He who removes from a believer one of his difficulties of this world, Allah will remove one of his troubles on
        the Day of Resurrection; and he who finds relief for a hard-pressed person, Allah will make things easy for him
        on the Day of Resurrection; he who covers up (the faults and sins) of a Muslim, Allah will cover up (his faults
        and sins) in this world and in the Hereafter. Allah supports His slave as long as the slave is supportive of his
        brother; and he who treads the path in search of knowledge, Allah makes that path easy, leading to Jannah for
        him; the people who assemble in one of the houses of Allah, reciting the Book of Allah, learning it and
        teaching, there descends upon them the tranquillity, and mercy covers them, the angels flock around them, and
        Allah mentions them in the presence of those near Him; and he who lags behind in doing good deeds, his noble
        lineage will not make him go ahead.'' [Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        "Abu Musa Al-Ash`ari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Whenever a needy person would come to the Prophet
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ), he would turn to those who were present and say, If you make intercession
        for him, you will be" rewarded, because Allah decreed what He likes by the tongue of His Messenger". [Al-Bukhari
        and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Ibn `Abbas (May Allah bepleased with them), reported in connection with the case of Barirah (May Allah
        bepleased with her) and her husband: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said to her, "It is better
        for you to go back to your husband.'' She asked: "O Messenger of Allah, do you order me to do so.'' He replied,
        "I only intercede'' She then said: "I have no need for him". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) said, "On
        every joint of man, there is charity, on everyday when the sun rises: doing justice between two men is charity,
        and assisting a man to ride an animal or to load his luggage on it is charity; and a good word is charity, every
        step which one takes towards (the mosque for) Salat is charity, and removing harmful things from the way is
        charity". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        Umm Kulthum bint `Uqbah (رضي الله عنها) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        said, 'The person who (lies) in order to conciliate between people is not a liar, when he conveys good or says
        (something) good". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>
        `Aishah (رضي الله عنها) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ ) heard the voices of
        altercation of two disputants at the door; both the voices were quite loud. One was asking the other to make his
        debts little (so that he could pay them) and was pleading with him to show leniency to him, whereupon the (other
        one) said: "By Allah, I will not do that". Then there came Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ )
        to them and said, "Where is he who swore by Allah that he would not do good?'' He said: "O Messenger of Allah,
        it is me. Now he may do as he desires". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
</hadiths>