<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hadiths>
    <hadith>Narrated 'Umar bin Al-Khattab (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ), reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The deeds are considered by the intentions, and a person will get the reward according to his
        intention. So whoever emigrated for Allah and His Messenger, his emigration will be for Allah and His Messenger;
        and whoever emigrated for worldly benefits or for a woman to marry, his emigration would be for what he
        emigrated for." [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Narrated 'A`ishah (رَضِيَ اَللَّهُ عَنْهَا) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said, "An army will raid the Ka`bah and when it reaches a desert land, all of them will be swallowed up by the
        earth.'' She asked; "O Messenger of Allah! Why all of them?'' He answered, "All of them will be swallowed by the
        earth but they will be raised for Judgement according to their intentions.''[Al-Bukhari and Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Jabir bin Abdullah Al-Ansari (رضي الله عنهما) reported: We accompanied the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) in an expedition when he said, "There are some men in Al-Madinah who are with you wherever you march
        and whichever valley you cross. They have not joined you in person because of their illness.'' In another
        version he said: "They share the reward with you.'' [Muslim]. "
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Ma`n bin Yazid bin Akhnas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) (he, his father and his grandfather, all were Companions)
        reported: My father set aside some dinars for charity and gave them to a man in the mosque. I went to that man
        and took back those dinars. He said: "I had not intended you to be given.'' So we went to Messenger of Allah
        (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ), and put forth the matter before him. He said to my father, "Yazid, you have
        been rewarded for what you intended.'' And he said to me, "Ma`n, you are entitled to what you have taken.''
        [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) narrated: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Allah does not look at your figures, nor at your attire but He looks at your hearts and accomplishments".
        [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Musa Al-Ash`ari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        was asked about who fights in the battlefield out of valour, or out of zeal, or out of hypocrisy, which of this
        is considered as fighting in the cause of Allah? He said: "He who fights in order that the Word of Allah remains
        the supreme, is considered as fighting in the cause of Allah". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Bakrah Ath-Thaqafi (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said:
        "When two Muslims are engaged in a combat against each other with their sword's and one is killed, both are
        doomed to Hell". I said, "O Messenger of Allah! As to the one who kills, it is understandable, but why the slain
        one?" He (PBUH) replied: "He was eager to kill his opponent". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>`Abdullah bin `Abbas (رضي الله عنهما) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said
        that Allah, the Glorious, said: "Verily, Allah (SWT) has ordered that the good and the bad deeds be written
        down. Then He explained it clearly how (to write): He who intends to do a good deed but he does not do it, then
        Allah records it for him as a full good deed, but if he carries out his intention, then Allah the Exalted,
        writes it down for him as from ten to seven hundred folds, and even more. But if he intends to do an evil act
        and has not done it, then Allah writes it down with Him as a full good deed, but if he intends it and has done
        it, Allah writes it down as one bad deed". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I heard Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        saying: "By Allah, I seek Allah's forgiveness and repent to Him more than seventy times a day.'' [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Al-Agharr bin Yasar Al-Muzani (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) narrated that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said: "Turn you people in repentance to Allah and beg pardon of Him. I turn to Him in
        repentance a hundred times a day". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Anas bin Malik Al-Ansari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) the servant of the Messenger of Allah narrated: Messenger of
        Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Verily, Allah is more delighted with the repentance of His slave
        than a person who lost his camel in a desert land and then finds it (unexpectedly)". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Musa Al-Ash`ari (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said:
        "Allah, the Exalted, will continue to stretch out His Hand in the night so that the sinners of the day may
        repent, and continue to stretch His Hand in the daytime so that the sinners of the night may repent, until the
        sun rises from the west". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) narrated: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "He
        who repents before the sun rises from the west, Allah will forgive him". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>`Abdullah bin `Umar bin Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنهما) reported that: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Allah accepts a slave's repentance as long as the latter is not on his death bed (that is,
        before the soul of the dying person reaches the throat)." [At-Tirmidhi, who categorised it as Hadith Hasan].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Ibn 'Abbas and Anas bin Malik (رضي الله عنهما) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) said, "If a son of Adam were to own a valley full of gold, he would desire to have two. Nothing can
        fill his mouth except the earth (of the grave). Allah turns with mercy to him who turns to Him in repentance."
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Allah, the Exalted, smiles at two men, one of them killed the other and both will enter Jannah. The first is
        killed by the other while he is fighting in the Cause of Allah, and thereafter Allah will turn in mercy to the
        second and guide him to accept Islam and then he dies as a Shaheed (martyr) fighting in the Cause of Allah.''
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Malik Al-Harith bin Asim Al-Ash`ar (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said: "Wudu' is half of Salah; the utterance of (Al-hamdu lillah - all praise belongs
        to Allah) fills the Scales of good actions; the utterance of (Subhan Allah wa Al-hamdu lillah) (Allah is far
        removed from every imperfection and all praise belongs to Allah) fills the space between the heavens and the
        earth, and Salat (prayer) is light; and charity is the proof of Faith; and endurance is light, and the Qur'an is
        a plea in your favour or against you. Every person departs; he either ransoms it or puts it into perdition".
        [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Sa'id Al-Khudri (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: Certain people of the Ansar asked the Messenger of
        Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) and he gave them; then they again asked him and he gave them until all
        what he possessed was exhausted. Then the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Whatever wealth I
        have, I will not withhold from you. Whosoever would be chaste and modest; Allah will keep him chaste and modest
        and whosoever would seek selfsufficiency, Allah will make him self-sufficient; and whosoever would be patient,
        Allah will give him patience, and no one is granted a gift better and more comprehensive than patience".
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Yahya Suhaib bin Sinan (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "How wonderful is the case of a believer; there is good for him in everything and this
        applies only to a believer. If prosperity attends him, he expresses gratitude to Allah and that is good for him;
        and if adversity befalls him, he endures it patiently and that is better for him". [Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: When the last illness of Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) made him unconscious, Fatimah (May Allah be pleased with her) exclaimed: "Ah, the distress of my dear
        father.'' He (PBUH) said, "There will be no distress for your father after today". When he died she said: "My
        father, Allah has called you back and you have responded to His Call. O father! Garden of Firdaus is your abode.
        O father! We announce to Jibril your death.'' When he was buried, she said: "Are you satisfied now that you put
        earth over (the grave of) Messenger of Allah (PBUH)?'' [Al-Bukhari]
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) passed by a woman who was
        crying over a grave and said, "Fear Allah and be patient.'' She said, "Away from me! My calamity has not
        befallen you and you are not aware of it.'' The woman was later told that it was the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ
        عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) (who had advised her). She came to his door where she found no doorkeeper. She said, "(I am
        sorry) I did not know you.'' Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "Patience is (becoming)
        only at the first (stroke) of grief". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Allah, the Exalted, says: 'I have no reward other than Jannah for a believing slave of Mine who remains patient
        for My sake when I take away his beloved one from among the inhabitants of the world". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>`Aishah (رَضِيَ اَللَّهُ عَنْهَا) reported: I asked the Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        about pestilence and he said, "It is a punishment which Allah sends upon whomsoever He wills, but Allah has made
        it as a mercy to the believers. Anyone who remains in a town which is plagued with pestilence maintaining
        patience expecting the reward from Allah, and knowing that nothing will befall him other than what Allah has
        foreordained for him, he would receive a reward of Shaheed". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) said: I heard the Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) saying,
        "Allah, the Glorious and Exalted said: `When I afflict my slave in his two dear things (i.e., his eyes), and he
        endures patiently, I shall compensate him for them with Jannah.". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>`Ata' bin Abu Rabah reported: Ibn `Abbas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) asked him whether he would like that he
        should show him a woman who is from the people Jannah. When he replied that he certainly would, he said, "This
        black woman, who came to the Prophet (PBUH) and said, `I suffer from epilepsy and during fits my body is
        exposed, so make supplication to Allah for me.' He (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) replied: 'If you wish you
        endure it patiently and you be rewarded with Jannah, or if you wish, I shall make supplication to Allah to cure
        you?' She said, 'I shall endure it.' Then she added: `But my body is exposed, so pray to Allah that it may not
        happen.' He (Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)) then supplicated for her." [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>`Abdullah bin Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I can still recall as if I am seeing the Messenger of
        Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) resembling one of the Prophets whose people scourged him and shed his
        blood, while he wiped blood from his face, he said: "O Allah! Forgive my people, because they certainly do not
        know". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Sa`id and Abu Hurairah (رضي الله عنهما) reported that the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said: "Never a believer is stricken with a discomfort, an illness, an anxiety, a grief or mental worry or even
        the pricking of a thorn but Allah will expiate his sins on account of his patience". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Ibn Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I visited the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) when he
        was suffering fever. I said, "You seem to be suffering greatly, O Messenger of Allah.'' The Prophet (صَلَّى
        اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) replied, "Yes, I suffer as much as two persons.'' I said, "Is that because you have a
        double reward?'' He replied that was so and then said, "No Muslim is afflicted by a harm, be it the pricking of
        a thorn or something more (painful than that), but Allah thereby causes his sins to fall away just as a tree
        sheds its leaves". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ)
        said: "He whom Allah intends good, He makes him to suffer from some affliction". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "Let not one of you wish for death because of a misfortune which befalls him. If he cannot help doing so, he
        should say: 'O Allah, keep me alive as long as You know that life is better for me, and make me die when death
        is better for me". [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported that: The Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said,
        "When Allah intends good for His slave, He punishes him in this world, but when He intends an evil for His
        slave, He does not hasten to take him to task but calls him to account on the Day of Resurrection.''
        [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The
        strong man is not one who is good at wrestling, but the strong man is one who controls himself in a fit of
        rage.'' [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Sulaiman bin Surad (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: I was sitting with the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ
        وَسَلَّمَ) when two men began to quarrel and curse each other and the face of one of them turned red and the
        veins of his neck were swollen (from rage). Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "I know
        of a word, if he were to utter that, his rage would vanish and that is: A`udhu billahi minash-Shaitan nir-rajim
        (I seek refuge with Allah from Satan, the accursed).'' So they (Companions) said to him: "The Prophet (PBUH)
        tells you to utter: 'I seek refuge with Allah from Satan, the accursed". [Al-Bukhariand Muslim].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Mu`adh bin Anas (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: The Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "The one
        who suppresses anger and has the power to give effect to it, will be called out by Allah, the Exalted, to the
        forefront of the creatures on the Day of Resurrection and he will be asked to choose any of the virgins (Hur) of
        his liking". [Abu Dawud and At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: A man asked the Prophet (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) for
        an advice and he (PBUH) said, "Do not get angry". The man repeated that several times and he replied, "Do not
        get angry". [Al-Bukhari].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Abu Hurairah (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "A
        Muslim, male or female, continues to remain under trial in respect of his life, property and offspring until he
        faces Allah, the Exalted, with no sin record". [At-Tirmidhi].
    </hadith>
    <hadith>Ibn Mas`ud (رَضِيَ اللهُ عَنْهُ) reported: Messenger of Allah (صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ) said, "You
        will see after me favouritism and things which you will disapprove of.'' They submitted: "What do you order us
        to do (under such circumstances)?'' He replied, "Discharge your obligations and ask your rights from Allah".
        [Al-Bukhari and Muslim].
    </hadith>
</hadiths>